Guide to the Backus Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Backus family papers
1728-1893
MS 47
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.5
(11 boxes, 1 folio)
The papers are composed of correspondence, legal and financial papers, and memorabilia of several descendants and relatives of Samuel (1693-1740) and Elizabeth Tracey Backus of Norwich, Connecticut. Papers of Samuel Backus's grandson James, his partner Rufus Backus, and James's brother-in-law Dudley Woodbridge concern mercantile establishments, commerce, and shipping in Norwich following the Revolutionary War. There is also correspondence between several family members of this generation, as well as a diary of James's brother Elijah, which he kept while studying in New Haven (1778). Papers of James's son William Woodbridge Backus document his investments and financial dealings, genealogical interests, and philanthropic endeavors for the last fifteen years of his life.
Backus family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from H. A. Armstrong, 1942-1946; Hurwitz, 1945; Miele, 1958; and R. Hooker, 1962.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series: I. General Correspondence, 1769-1889. II. William W. Backus Files, 1820-1892. III. Miscellaneous Papers, 1728-1893.
Scope and Contents
The Backus Family Papers are composed of correspondence, legal and financial papers, and memorabilia of several direct descendants and more distant relatives of Samuel (1693-1740) and Elizabeth Tracey Backus of Norwich, Connecticut. Papers of Samuel Backus's grandson James Backus, his partner Rufus Backus, and James's brother-in-law Dudley Woodbridge concern mercantile establishments, commerce, and shipping in Norwich following the Revolutionary War. There is also a diary of James's brother Elijah, which he kept while studying in New Haven (1778), as well as correspondence between several family members of this generation. Papers of James's son William Woodbridge Backus (1803-1892) document his investments and financial dealings, genealogical interests, and philanthropic endeavors for the last fifteen years of his life.
The papers, which the Yale Library purchased between 1942 and 1962 from several dealers, are arranged in three series: I. General Correspondence, 1769-1889; II. William W. Backus Files, 1820-1892; III. Miscellaneous Papers, 1728-1893.
All series contain correspondence and legal and financial papers of Backus family members. Series I and III contain proportionally more material relating to James and Rufus Backus, Dudley Woodbridge and the earlier generations of Backus family members, while papers in Series II relate predominantly, though not exclusively, to William Woodbridge Backus (1803-1892).
Series I, GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE, begins with three boxes of correspondence and other papers which are arranged in alphabetical order. Most of the folder headings refer to the author of the letter but in several instances the letters are grouped by recipient. Most of the earliest letters and documents concern Dudley Woodbridge's mercantile interests, and correspondents include suppliers, customers, and shippers. After 1791 the business correspondence, bills, accounts, and notes are those of James and Rufus Backus's businesses including the store in Norwich and shipping from the West Indies.
The Alphabetical section also includes correspondence of additional family members. Many letters are addressed to Frances Backus, James's daughter, who lived with her brother William Woodbridge Backus in Yantic, Connecticut. Frances's brother Henry T. Backus, who was a lawyer in Detroit and a judge in the Arizona Territory, is a frequent correspondent. Other family correspondents include Marian Griswold Chandler Lane Ely and James's daughter Sarah. Folder 8 contains letters of Charles Backus, a cousin and minister in Somers, Connecticut, to fellow clergyman John H. Church in Pelham, New Hampshire.
At the end of Series I there is one box of correspondence and financial and legal papers arranged in chronological order. The Chronological section contains proportionally more accounts and other financial papers than the Alphabetical, but it spans the same time period, and subject matter. Several business correspondents including Nathaniel and John Tracy, Giles Mumford, Joseph Woodbridge, Isaac Cock, and Adgate and Company, are represented in both sections. Folder 186 contains records of Dudley Woodbridge's shipping concerns and several documents relate to the schooner Farmer under Captain Joseph Chapman. Several letters at the end of the section concern William Woodbridge Backus.
The first three boxes in Series II, arranged as the General section, are composed of William Woodbridge Backus's incoming correspondence for approximately the last 15 to 20 years of his life. The files, which are arranged in alphabetical order by the correspondents' names, concern Backus's financial investments and the publication of A Genealogical Memoir of the Backus Family. Many of the correspondents are investment advisers, lawyers, and public officials who write concerning Backus's interests in insurance, bank, coal, and railroad stocks, and mortgage loans for property in Kansas and Nebraska. There is some correspondence concerning estates of deceased family members, and there are several files concerning the accidental death, estate, and contested settlement of the estate of nephew James H. Backus (1851-1889) in California. Several correspondents write to acknowledge receipt of Backus's book, and correspondence with W. A. Briscoe and John T. Wait concerns Backus's philanthropic contributions.
The Family section in Series II includes a box of correspondence from several more distant kinsman, concerning family history or the estate of James H. Backus. Folders 283-305 contain drafts and copies of William Woodbridge Backus's outgoing letters. Many of these letters are replies to the incoming letters arranged in the General section. The Family section also includes William Woodbridge Backus's bank books and other financial records and a copy of his will showing his extensive charitable benefactions in Norwich.
Series III, MISCELLANEOUS-PAPERS contains additional financial papers of Dudley Woodbridge, James Backus, William Woodbridge Backus, and James H. Backus, as well as printed material and family memorabilia, In addition the series includes a diary kept by James Backus's brother Elijah in 1778. During this year Elijah Backus was studying in New Haven having graduated from Yale College in 1777. His diary includes entries in Latin concerning his daily activities as well as quotations and notes. A photostatic copy of the 1777 volume of Elijah Backus's diary is available in the Manuscripts and Archives Department (*Ydf +777ba)
Additional Backus Family material is located in the William Griswold Lane Memorial Collection (MS 189). There are also papers of the Backus Family in the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library and at the Yale Divinity School Library. The Woodbridge and Backus Collection in the Baker Library at the Harvard Business School also relates to the Backus family store in Norwich and contains papers of William Woodbridge Backus.
Biographical / Historical
James Backus was born in Norwich, Connecticut, in 1764. He was one of the first settlers of Ohio and a founder of the town of Marietta. He returned to Yantic, Connecticut, in 1791 to manage the family iron works and other businesses. He married Dorothy Church Chandler in 1793 and they had eight children. Backus died in 1816.
For a biography of James Backus, and a chart outlining the genealogical relations of the Backus family, please consult the Genealogical Chart and Biography.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Business; Families; General stores -- Connecticut; Retail trade -- Connecticut; Shipping -- Connecticut -- New London; Connecticut -- Commerce; Norwich (Conn.); Deeds; Diaries; Businessmen; Investment advisers; Merchants; Philanthropists; Backus, Dorothy Church Chandler, 1770-1847; Backus, Elijah, 1759-1811; Backus, Frances, 1806-1890; Backus, James, 1764-1816; Backus, Rufus, b. 1721; Backus, William Woodbridge, 1803-1892; Ely, Marian Griswold Chandler Lane, 1750-1829; Woodbridge, Dudley, 1747-1823; Backus family; Woodbridge family
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1769-1889; Series I; 1.75 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series is arranged in two sections: Alphabetical and Chronological.
  - Alphabetical
    - Abbe, Shubael, 1789 February 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abel, Rufus B., 1809 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Adams, David, 1799 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adams, Jonathan, 1795, 1796 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Adgate, A. and Company, 1792 November (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Anthony, Joseph and Company, 1799 May 13 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ashbey, ________, 1822 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Backus, Charles, 1799-1803 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Backus, Dorothy Chandler, [1820] August 10 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Backus, Elijah (1726-1798), 1769, 1788, 1800, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Backus, Elijah (1759-1811), 1792 April 16, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Backus, Frances, 1814-1889 (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
    - Backus, Henry, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Backus, Henry T., 1855-1877, undated (Box 1, Folder 16-18)
    - Backus, James, 1791-1831 (Box 1, Folder 19-24)
    - Backus, Juliana Trumbull, 1843 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Backus, Lucy, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Backus, Mary M., 1818-1821, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Backus, Matthew, 1800 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Backus, Rufus, 1783-1796 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Backus, Rufus and James, 1792 August 4 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Backus, Sarah, 1823-1831, undated (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
    - Backus, Sylvanus, 1792 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Baker, John, 1787 October 5 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Bastian, Warington, 1832 September 13 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Bentley, Robert, 1772 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Blanchard, John D., 1793-1795 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Bolles, John, 1793 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Bonne, George and Sons, 1793 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Bowen, Jabez, 1793 May 29 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Breed, Shubael, 1802 November 12 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Breed, Simeon, 1809 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Broome, John, 1793-1799 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Bruce, Stephen, 1784 November 8 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Bull, John, 1808-1817 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Bull, William, 1812-1829 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Carey, James, 1793 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Carneau, Sam, 1786 June 9 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Carpenter, Daniel, 1779-1799 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Chappell, Edward, 1787 September 25 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Chappell, Mary A., 1873-1884 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Chesebrough, David, 1771 September 23 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Christopher, Peter, 1812 April 14 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Cock, Isaac, 1796-1812 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Coit, Benjamin, 1799 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Coit, Elisha and William, 1799 April 5 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Coit, William, 1783 January 5 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Coles, William H., 1836-1837 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Converse, John, 1799 July 17 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Coolidge, Joseph and Son, 1799 July 26 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Corp, Samuel, 1793-1804 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      General
      See also: box 1, Folder 22
    - Cushing, Benjamin, 1792-1794 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Dennis, George, 1806 August 26 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Deshons, Daniel, 1793 July 6 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Dimach, Shubael, 1796 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Dunham, A., 1799 November 18 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Elderkin, Bela, 1770 August 24 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Ely, B., 1793 October 2 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Ely, Hannah (Chandler), 1812-1821 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Document concerning Justin Ely, 1813 May 25 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Ely, Marian (Griswold) Chandler Lane, 1814-1824 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Ely, Theodore, 1817-1829 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Fitch, John, 1789 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Frink, Angelina, 1839, 1859, undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Frink, Harvey, 1809-1810 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Frink, Juliana, 1867-1877 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Frink, Ursula (Chandler), 1817-1819 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Frink, Henry C., 1829 September 7 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Gilbert, John, Jr., 1781 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Green, Joshua, 1778 November 28 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Griswold, Matthew V., 1822-1829 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Hallam, Edward and Company, 1793, 1799 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Hibbard, Silas, 1797 September 8 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Higginson, L., 1812 January 16 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Hoppin, Benjamin, 1804 June 23 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - House, Elijah, 1788, 1793 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - House, Simon, 1793 October 24 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Howland and Coit, 1787 March 24 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Hubbard, David G., 1799 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Hunt, E. and Son, 1799 February 4 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Huntington, Andrew, 1799 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Huntington, Benjamin, Jr., 1799 April 11 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Huntington, Elisha, 1799 November 15 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Huntington, Henry, 1793, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Jocelyn, Samuel R., 1791 August 1 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Jones, Joel, Jr., 1789 January 19 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Jones, Joel, Jr. and Company, 1789 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Kies, George W., 1809 May 13 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - King, Thomas, 1799 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Lamson and Fraser, 1784 February 17 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Lane, Ebenezer (1749-1808), 1799 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Lane, Ebenezer (1793-1866), 1848 November 4 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Lanman, Charles J., 1816 July 24 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Lanman, James, 1797-1829, undated (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Lanman, Marian G., undated (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Lathrop and Eels, 1799 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Lee, Sarah Backus, 1827-1834 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Lee, Thomas, 1771-1784 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Little, John, 1801 June 12 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Little, Jonathan, 1804 December 19 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Little, William, 1793-1798 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Lord, Jabez, 1788 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Martin, Anderson, 1789 March 31 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - McCurdy, Lynde, 1793 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - McEvers, James, [1786?] (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - McGowty, John, 1811 March 4 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Miller, Eleazer, 1788 July 4 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Mumford, Giles, 1782-1793 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Mumford, Thomas, 1799 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Neilson, William, 1793 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Neilson, William and Company, 1793, 1799 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Otis, Joseph, 1799-1804 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Page, William, 1800 October 29 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Paine, Luther, 1795 October 13 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Parkman, Samuel, 1784 November 1 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Parsons, Mansfield, 1784 April 4 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Pecks, Beala, 1814 January 26 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Perkins, Andrew, 1793 August 13 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Perkins, Andrew and Joseph, 1793 August 16 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Perkins, Joseph, 1793 September 26 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Phelps, Ichabod, 1784 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Phoenix, Daniel, 1775, 1776 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Proctor, John, 1778 September 14 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Richards, John, 1777 February 11 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Ripley, Hez., 1779 June 24 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Ripley, John, 1783 September 22 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Rockwell, Charles, 1799 December 4 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Rodman, Daniel, 1784-1793 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Rogers and Aspinwall, 1793 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Rogers and Woolsey, 1793 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Rogers, S. Mumford, 1806 April 12 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Rogers, Zabdiel, 1792, 1793 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Rouse, J.H., 1831 November 7 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Rowlett, Corp and Company, 1789, 1793 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Russell, Joseph and William, 1784, 1785 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Saltonstall, Gelston, 1793 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Saltonstall, Gilbert, 1793, 1796 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Scholfield, John, 1811-1814 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Scott, John, 1774 June 8 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Sidney, William, 1774 August 19 (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Smith, Richard, 1783, 1784 (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Snow, Sam, 1789 February 13 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Snow, W.Z., 1799 August 24 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Spalding, Asa, 1788, 1799 (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Sprague, Elijah, 1784 April 13 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Stockbridge, David, 1800 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Storer, Ebenezer, 1779-1788 (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - Taintor, John, 1793 September 17 (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - Thomas, Joseph, 1794 November 1 (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Tracy, Nathaniel and John, 1782 January 22 (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Tucker, Richard D., 1804-1819 (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Tucker, Sally (Chandler), undated (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - Waldo, Nathan, 1773 May 17 (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - Waterman, Asa, 1775 August 8 (Box 3, Folder 164)
    - Watson and Greenleaf, 1789 February 20 (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Watson, Jacob, 1783 June 19 (Box 3, Folder 166)
    - Watson, James, 1787 December 29 (Box 3, Folder 167)
    - Wattles, Daniel, undated (Box 3, Folder 168)
    - Whalley and Woodham, 1793 June 1 (Box 3, Folder 169)
    - Wheat, Samuel, 1787-1799 (Box 3, Folder 170)
    - White and Wardell, 1793 November 29 (Box 3, Folder 171)
    - White, Charles C., 1785 December 25 (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - Williams, Joseph, 1799 (Box 3, Folder 173)
    - Wills, James, 1809 May 17 (Box 3, Folder 174)
    - Wood, Will, 1793 April 4 (Box 3, Folder 175)
    - Woodbridge and Snow, 1793 February 1 (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - Woodbridge, Dudley, 1771-1801, undated (Box 3, Folder 177)
    - Woodbridge, Joseph, 1777-1785 (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - Woodbridge, Lucy Backus, undated (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - Woodbridge, Samuel, 1804 September 7 (Box 3, Folder 180)
    - Woodbridge, William, 1782-1831 (Box 3, Folder 181)
    - Woods, Abiel, 1792 September 20 (Box 3, Folder 182)
    - Miscellaneous, 1782-1839, n.d (Box 3, Folder 183)
  - Chronological
    - 1771 - 1878, undated (Box 4, Folder 184-194)
- WILLIAM W. BACKUS FILES, 1820-1892; Series II; 2 linear feet (5 boxes)
  This series is arranged in two sections: General and Family.
  - General
    - A - B, 1880-1892 (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - Abbott, Hattie E., 1891-1892 (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - American Ancestry, 1890, undated (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - American Coal Company, 1870-1886 (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - Babbitt, F.B., 1891-1892 (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - Backus, Abner Lord, 1885-1892 (Box 5, Folder 200-202)
    - Bailey, E.S., 1876-1891 (Box 5, Folder 203)
    - Barnes and Selby, 1889-1892 (Box 5, Folder 204-207)
    - Bell, H.B., 1890-1892 (Box 5, Folder 208)
    - Biebighiser, Charles, 1891-1892 (Box 5, Folder 209)
    - Boles, T.T., 1890-1892 (Box 5, Folder 210)
    - Branson, W.H., 1891 (Box 5, Folder 211)
    - Briscoe, W.A., 1891-1892 (Box 5, Folder 212)
    - C - D, 1882-1892 (Box 5, Folder 213)
    - Campbell, Charles M., 1891 (Box 5, Folder 214)
    - Campbell, S.S., 1890-1891 (Box 5, Folder 215)
    - Coit, George D., 1877-1888 (Box 5, Folder 216)
    - Dowling, Morgan E., 1890-1892 (Box 5, Folder 217)
    - F - G, 1881-1892 (Box 5, Folder 218)
    - Fitch, Stephen, 1845-1846 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    - Fowler, Alex D., 1890 (Box 5, Folder 220)
    - Freese, John P., 1891 (Box 5, Folder 221)
    - Grant, Henry L., 1881-1882 (Box 5, Folder 222)
    - H, 1883-1892 (Box 5, Folder 223)
    - Hillier, E.C., 1879-1883 (Box 5, Folder 224)
    - Hyde, Lewis A., 1887-1892, undated (Box 5, Folder 225)
    - J - L, 1870-1892 (Box 5, Folder 226)
    - Jennings, William, Jr., 1880-1884 (Box 5, Folder 227)
    - Jones, J.W., 1892 (Box 6, Folder 228)
    - Keep, Robert P., 1890, undated (Box 6, Folder 229)
    - Kern, Charles P., 1890-1892 (Box 6, Folder 230)
    - Ladd, S.J.P., 1868-1892 (Box 6, Folder 231)
    - Lanman, Charles James, 1849 (Box 6, Folder 232)
    - Latting, W.S., 1888-1889 (Box 6, Folder 233)
    - Lippitt, Costello, 1887-1890 (Box 6, Folder 234)
    - Little, D.T., 1891 (Box 6, Folder 235)
    - Littlefield, George E., 1890-1891 (Box 6, Folder 236)
    - Locke, C.H., 1877 (Box 6, Folder 237)
    - Lucas, Clinton W., 1885-1892, undated (Box 6, Folder 238-243)
    - Lucas, Frederick C., 1888-1890 (Box 6, Folder 244)
    - M - O, 1881-1892, undated (Box 6, Folder 245)
    - Madison, Edward H., 1892 (Box 6, Folder 246)
    - McElvaine, Emily, 1890-1891 (Box 6, Folder 247)
    - Moffitt, D.W., 1891-1892 (Box 6, Folder 248)
    - Osborn, C.F., 1892 (Box 6, Folder 249)
    - P - Q, 1882-1892 (Box 7, Folder 250)
    - Pasco, H., 1891-1892 (Box 7, Folder 251)
    - Patten, Mark F., 1890-1891 (Box 7, Folder 252)
    - Patterson. A.A., 1890 (Box 7, Folder 253)
    - R - T, 1870-1892, n.d (Box 7, Folder 254)
    - Rossiter, Mrs. George, 1877-1891 (Box 7, Folder 255)
    - Salisbury, Evelyn McCurdy, 1890 (Box 7, Folder 256)
    - Schwerin, Max, Jr., 1874-1889 (Box 7, Folder 257-258)
    - Showalter Mortgage Company, 1877-1892 (Box 7, Folder 259-260)
    - Smith, T.C.H., 1889-1892 (Box 7, Folder 261)
    - Smythe, A.H., 1890 November 1 (Box 7, Folder 262)
    - Spalding, J.A., 1891 (Box 7, Folder 263)
    - W - Z, 1841-1891 (Box 7, Folder 264)
    - Wait, John T., 1889-1892, undated (Box 7, Folder 265)
    - Warner, Earl, 1883-1884 (Box 7, Folder 266)
    - Woodbridge, John T., 1889-1892, undated (Box 7, Folder 267-268)
    - Form letters, 1870-1891 (Box 7, Folder 269)
    - Acknowledgements for Illustrated Biograph y, 1891-1892 (Box 7, Folder 270-271)
  - Family
    - Backus, Alex, 1888-1892 (Box 8, Folder 272)
    - Backus, Brody E., 1891 September 24 (Box 8, Folder 273)
    - Backus, Elizabeth M., 1889 (Box 8, Folder 274)
    - Backus, Henry Clinton, 1887-1891 (Box 8, Folder 275)
    - Backus, Henry T., 1829-1873 (Box 8, Folder 276)
    - Backus, James H., 1882-1889, undated (Box 8, Folder 277)
    - Backus, Lucretia A., 1888, undated (Box 8, Folder 278)
    - Backus, Samuel R., 1888-1892 (Box 8, Folder 279)
    - Woodbridge, Dudley B., 1890-1891 (Box 8, Folder 280)
    - Woodbridge, Maria Morgan, 1890 July 22 (Box 8, Folder 281)
    - Woodbridge, William L., 1890-1892, undated (Box 8, Folder 282)
    - Drafts, 1881-1892 (Box 8, Folder 283-302)
    - Drafts, undated (Box 9, Folder 303-305)
    - Letters not to or from members of the Backus family, 1890-1892, undated (Box 9, Folder 306)
    - Unidentified correspondence, 1888, 1892, undated (Box 9, Folder 307)
    - Notes, General, undated (Box 9, Folder 308-309)
    - Account, 1820 (Box 9, Folder 310)
    - Will, undated (Box 9, Folder 311)
    - Bankbooks, 1853-1890 (Box 9, Folder 312)
- MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS, 1728-1893; Series III; .75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  This series is arranged by creator or record type.
  - Backus, James, 1798-1810 (Box 10, Folder 313)
  - Backus, Elijah (1759-1811): diary, 1778 (Box 10, Folder 314)
  - Deeds, 1728-1864 (Box 10, Folder 315)
    See also: Deeds, maps, and financial papers
  - Financial papers, 1749-1889 (Box 10, Folder 316-323)
  - Financial papers, 1890-1893, undated (Box 11, Folder 324-326)
  - Printed material, undated (Box 11, Folder 327-328)
  - Miscellanea, undated (Box 11, Folder 329-332)
  - Deeds, maps, and financial papers, 1728-1859 (Box 12)